Robert Hillyer Papers
Robert Hillyer Papers
- Literary correspondence
  - Johnson, Thomas H., 1955-1959; 25 Letters (Box 3)
    2 Apr. 1958 - ALS Comments briefly on Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems, relates anecdote concerning Thomas Reed Powell; comments on literary work in progress.
    2 Jan. 1958 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems.
    6 Jan. 1958 - TLS with holograph addenda. Comments on introduction to book on Emily Dickinson.
    29 Feb. 1958 - ALS
    19 Mar. 1958 - ALS Comments on response to publication of Emily Dickinson book.
    4 May 1958 - ALS
    5 Jun. 1958 - ALS
    26 Jun. 1958 - ALS Mentions review in Times Literary Supplement concerning Emily Dickinson.
    16 Jun. 1958 - TLS
    12 Jul. 1958 - ALS
    1 Sept. 1958 - ALS
    14 May 1959 - ALS
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1937; 1949; 2 Letters (Box 3)
    17 Sept. 1937 - TLS Analyses Hillyer's work with comments on its implications for modern verse.
    20 Jun. 1949 - TLS Supports Hillyer's stand on Ezra Pound and Bollingen Award.
  - Keith, Joseph Joel, 1958; 1960; 2 Letters (Box 3)
    27 Feb. 1958 - ALS Discusses current condition of modern American poetry in relation to various magazines.
    6 Jan. 1960 - ALS
  - Keller, Helen, 1947; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    12 Dec. 1947 - TLS Appreciates Hillyer's poetry.
  - Kent, Louis, 1945; 1947-1953,; 1955,; 1957,; 1961; 83 Letters (Box 3)
    Undated 1945 - ALS Analyzes new Hillyer poems "The Inscription," "The Aftertone," "Chanson Triste," "The PhD's."
    1 Nov. 1945 - ALS Informs Hillyer of author's success in selling two poems to The New Yorker.
    21 Nov. 1945 - TLS Encloses poems and gives detailed description of author's background and literary development.
    25 Feb. 1947 - TLS Discusses future publication of his own poems, comments on Hillyer's "Never Come Back" and outlines aid Hillyer gave to the launching of Kent's literary career.
    10 Apr. 1947 - ALS Discusses despondency over literary activity and various literary figures including Hillyer.
    29 Jun. 1947 - TLS Comments on book by Marya Zaturenska and Horace Gregory and encloses poems and some magazines for Hillyer's inspection.
    10 Sept. 1947 - TLS Criticizes poem of Hillyer's at length and mentions Kent's difficulties publishing.
    21 Sept. 1947 - ALS Lengthy appreciation of Hillyer's new book with criticism of some of the poems.
    12 Oct. 1947 - TLS Further comments on Hillyer's new book and quotes opinion of friend on same.
    3 Nov. 1947 - TLS Describes Grant Sanders whose opinion was included in preceding letter, and also describes Kent's life.
    4 Dec. 1947 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's work; includes poem "Latitudes" with explanation of same.
    14 Dec. 1947 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's "The Garden of Artemis"; criticizes Hillyer's work at length.
    21 Jan. 1948 - TLS Comments on Kent's current success and failure to gain publication.
    10 Feb. 1948 - ALS
    7 Mar. 1948 - ALS Discusses further publication difficulties with quotation of letter from John Crowe Ransom; and mention of young poet Laurie Lee.
    13 Jun. 1948 - ALS Discusses reviews of poet Laurie Lee's book in relation to current condition of American literary scene.
    25 Jun. 1948 - ALS Discusses attitude toward forthcoming publication of poems.
    13 Jul. 1948 - TLS Encloses manuscript of poems.
    26 Sept. 1948 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on "The Aftersong."
    12 Oct. 1948 - ALS Comments on relationship with Ted Weeks of The Atlantic Monthly and John Crowe Ransom.
    25 Oct. 1948 - ALS Mentions reaction to recently published Kent poem and comments on review of a Peter Viereck book by Selden Rodman.
    7 Nov. 1948 - ALS Detailed appreciation of The Death of Captain Nemo and comments on unnamed sonnets of Hillyer's.
    21 Nov. 1948 - ALS Lengthy appreciation and criticism of part two of Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo.
    13 Dec. 1948 - ALS Specifically comments on Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo, discusses author's current literary activity, and refers to T. S. Eliot, Ezra Pound, and W. B. Yeats.
    1 Jan. 1949 - TLS Comments further on Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo; encloses two poems.
    11 Jan. 1949 - ALS Criticizes The Death of Captain Nemo section by section and encloses a list of line by line objections.
    6 Feb. 1949 - TLS Comments further on The Death of Captain Nemo and describes Inez Boulton; mentions sale of two poems; and describes books recently sent by Laurie Lee.
    13 Feb. 1949 - ALS Analyzes The Death of Captain Nemo.
    24 Feb. 1949 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's meeting with Edith Sitwell and his aid in Kent's admission to The Poetry Society of America; comments on Kent's current literary activity and reading.
    13 Mar. 1949 - TLS Describes revision of "Professor Mortimer" and mentions acceptance of "I. Scrivner" by Horizons magazine; encloses copy of "Professor Mortimer."
    1 Apr. 1949 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's articles in The Saturday Review of Literature on Ezra Pound and mentions Kent's work on his book.
    12 May 1949 - ALS Mentions Hillyer's efforts to obtain award for Kent and discusses current publication of poems by Kent and Peter Viereck; revised "Professor Mortimer" enclosed.
    12 Jun. 1949 - TLS Comments on and quotes from Hillyer's The Saturday Review of Literature article on Ezra Pound and comments on Yeats.
    1 Jul. 1949 - ALS Comments further and praise of Hillyer's article on Ezra Pound, and quotation of poem to be reprinted in Poetry Awards.
    4 Aug. 1949 - ALS Encourages Hillyer to retain faith in worth of The Death of Captain Nemo despite attacks resulting from articles on Ezra Pound in The Saturday Review of Literature.
    10 Aug. 1949 - TLS Encloses manuscript for forthcoming book and requests Hillyer's criticism.
    28 Aug. 1949 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's criticism of Kent's poems.
    30 Sept. 1949 - ALS Compares Kent's and Hillyer's attitude regarding manuscript and mentions adverse reviews of Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo.
    23 Oct. 1949 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's articles on Ezra Pound and comments on Kent's current reading.
    29 Nov. 1949 - TLS Mentions money received from Shelley Memorial Award and encloses poems.
    1 Jan. 1950 - TLS Discusses attack by Dos Passos and others on Hillyer's Ezra Pound articles, describes current literary activity, mentions Louise Bogan, Gwendolyn Brooks, John Crowe Ransom.
    22 Jan. 1950 - TLS Criticizes six Hillyer poems, with brief mention of Louise Townsend Nicholl and Peter Viereck's Conservatism Revisited; encloses copy of poem "Lullaby For A Squirrel."
    19 Feb. 1950 - ALS Comments on sale of Hillyer poem to The New Yorker and sale of Kent's "Lullaby For A Squirrel" to same; discusses demise of Tiger's Eye and change in editors at Poetry; poem enclosed.
    15 Mar. 1950 - ALS Describes Dylan Thomas' poetry reading in Washington; poems enclosed.
    16 Apr. 1950 - TLS Mentions forthcoming publication of book Declensions of The Air.
    23 Apr. 1950 - TLS Criticizes Hillyer's poem and comments on two Kent poems.
    25 May 1950 - ALS From Louis Kent's wife.
    25 May 1950 - ALS Describes anxiety over forthcoming publication of Declensions of The Air.
    4 Jun. 1950 - ALS Comments on Louise Townsend Nicholl.
    15 Jun. 1950 - ALS Discusses The Merry Go Round By The Falls.
    21 Jun. 1950 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's sale of "Under Great Trees" to The New Yorker.
    31 Jul. 1950 - ALS Discusses attempts to write blank verse and comments on possibility that his book will be reviewed by Inez Boulton in Poetry; two poems enclosed.
    27 Aug. 1950 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's participation in radio program on Dante, and mentions poems of Kent and Hillyer.
    17 Sept. 1950 - TLS Discusses current moods and encloses copy of recent poem. 51
    1 Oct. 1950 - ALS Discusses forthcoming publication of Declensions of The Air and criticizes
    29 Nov. 1950 - ALS unnamed Hillyer poem. Appreciation of Hillyer's work.
    15 Oct. 1950 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for his review of author's Declensions of The Air.
    14 Jan. 1951 - TLS Describes various reactions to Kent's book and encloses review of same; inquires about Academy Award to e.e. cummings.
    7 Mar. 1951 - ALS Comments on poem of James Wright and discusses Hillyer's criticisms.
    2 May 1951 - ALS Reviews trip to England.
    28 Jun. 1951 - ALS Discusses forthcoming unnamed Hillyer book.
    26 Aug. 1951 - TLS Mentions current reading and efforts of Poetry magazine to obtain review of Kent's book.
    28 Oct. 1951 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's financial and general condition, mentions publication in Kenyon Review of poems by James Wright.
    18 Dec. 1951 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's poem "Suburb By The Sea," Christopher Fry's A Sleep of Prisoners, and Peter and Katinka DeVries.
    23 Mar. 1952 - TLS Explains liking for Dylan Thomas and describes poetry reading of W. H. Auden and Robert Frost; encloses poems.
    4 May 1952 - ALS
    22 Jun. 1952 - TLS Praises Hillyer's poem "The Bats" and describes meeting with Ellen Borden Stevenson.
    12 Oct. 1952 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's criticisms of poems; encloses poem.
    28 Dec. 1952 - ALS Recounts amusing story about Sir Osbert Sitwell and mentions Josephine Tey's A Daughter of Time; encloses poem.
    23 Mar. 1953 - ALS Mentions sale of two poems to The New Yorker and recounts meeting Louis MacNiece.
    26 Jun. 1953 - Card AS Untitled poem.
    26 Jul. 1953 - TLS Mentions current literary activity; encloses poems.
    22 Nov. 1953 - ALS Mentions new writing project, and comments on various modern poets.
    30 Jan. 1955 - ALS Sends copies of The Spectator, Andrew Young's Collected Poems, The Annotator, and Kingsley Amis's Lucky Jim.
    11 Aug. 1955 - ALS
    9 Oct. 1955 - ALS Mentions Hillyer's date to read poetry in Washington and comments on Kent's inability to write poetry.
    28 Dec. 1955 - ALS Mentions Hillyer's recovery from auto accident.
    14 Sept. 1957 - ALS Agrees to send Hillyer some of the letters he has sent over the years for projected article.
    21 Sept. 1957 - TLS Encloses letters and comments on them; inquires after Hillyer protégés James Wright and James Gould Cozzens.
    15 Oct. 1957 - ALS Compares Hillyer letter to those of Horace Walpole and comments on review of unnamed Hillyer book.
    25 Apr. 1961 - TLS
    9 May 1961 - ALS Returns Hillyer letters and comments on In Pursuit of Poetry.
    4 Jul. 1961 - TLS Discusses earlier relationship to Hillyer and comments on Hillyer's Collected Poems and on review of same.
  - Kiernan, John, 1952; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    5 May 1952 - TLS
  - Kittredge, G. L., 1937; 1 Card (Box 3)
    26 Jun. 1937 - Signed Card with message in verse.
  - Knopf, Alfred A., 1949; 1956-1957,; 1959-1961; 31 Letters (Box 3)
    2 Feb. 1949 - TLS Describes reactions to Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo and mentions plans for publication; contract letter enclosed.
    12 Apr. 1949 - TLS Detailed explanation of difficulties related to publication of Kahlil Gibran's Tears and Laughter.
    7 Jun. 1949 - TLS Praises Hillyer's article on the Bollingen Award and raises further questions about the implications of the award.
    6 Mar. 1956 - TLS
    18 Jun. 1956 - TLS
    13 Jul. 1956 - TLS Accepts Hillyer's unidentified volume of verse for publication.
    13 Jul. 1956 - TLS
    20 Jul. 1956 - TLS
    25 Jul. 1956 - TLS
    15 Oct. 1956 - TLS
    8 Feb. 1957 - TLS
    11 Feb. 1957 - TLS
    21 Feb. 1957 - TLS
    4 Mar. 1957 - TLS
    20 Mar. 1957 - TLS Mentions copyright assignments for Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems and design of volume.
    27 Mar. 1957 - TLS Discusses production and design of Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems.
    17 Apr. 1957 - TLS Requests clarification on publication date of Hillyer poem, with copy of poem enclosed.
    29 Apr. 1957 - TLS
    29 Aug. 1957 - TLS
    16 Dec. 1957 - TLS Mentions Nobel and Pulitzer Prizes and books The Castle and The Trial.
    21 Aug. 1959 - TLS Mentions preparation for publication of Hillyer's Collected Poems.
    10 Sept. 1959 - TLS
    6 May 1959 - TLS Comments on request by McGraw-Hill firm that Hillyer publish In Pursuit of Poetry with them.
    20 Jul. 1959 - TLS Comments further on McGraw-Hill plans.
    21 Apr. 1960 - TLS Mentions proposed Hillyer volume Collected Poems and encloses statement on business future of Alfred A. Knopf, Incorporated.
    16 Jun. 1960 - TLS Mentions target date for publication of Hillyer's Collected Poems.
    31 May 1961 - TLS Encloses copy of letter from Peter Viereck.
    13 Jun. 1961 - TLS
    22 Jun. 1961 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's Collected Poems and In Pursuit of Poetry.
    5 Dec. 1961 - TLS Mentions further Hillyer's Collected Poems.
  - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1924; 1949; 3 Letters (Box 4)
    2 Oct. - TLS Requests possibility of speaking engagement.
    27 Jun. 1924 - TLS Mentions another speaking engagement and current literary activity.
    9 Jun. 1949 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on exposing fascism.
  - Leach, Henry Goddard, 1949; 1961; 4 Letters (Box 4)
    8 Jun. 1949 - ALS
    27 Dec. 1961 - TLS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Leon, Maurice, 1949; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    19 Jul. 1949 - TLS Discusses Jung's relationship to Nazism.
    29 Jul. 1949 - TLS Discusses Pound and Jung and encloses copy of letter from Harrison Smith.
  - Lowell, Amy, 1923-1925; 4 Letters, 1 Invitation (Box 4)
    2 Nov. 1923 - TLS Mentions impending speaking engagement, Hillyer's poem "Cow," and work by Lowell.
    15 Mar. 1924 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's unexplained poisoning and describes poetry reading given by Lowell.
    5 Jun. 1924 - TLS Mentions Hillyer letter defending her against critical attack.
    Apr. 1924 - Printed Invitation.
    13 Apr. 1925 - TLS
  - Lopatnikoff, Sally (Mrs. Nikolai), 1959; 2 letters (Box 4)
    mentions John Wheelwright, Sara Teasdale, Jack Wheelock, Vachel Lindsay, Robert Frost, also her collection of poetry The Stone and the Shell.
  - Luri, Herman, 1950; 1958,; 1961; 4 Letters (Box 4)
    21 Dec. 1950 - ALS Encloses musical setting of Hillyer's "The Dance will end at midnight" and "Uneventful Return" and names 19 other songs to which author has supplied settings.
    14 Dec. 1958 - ALS Appreciation of the work of Hillyer and mention of musical for Hillyer's "Here is My Book."
    3 Jun. 1961 - ALS
    20 Jan. 1961 - ALS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Lyle, Donald, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    15 Jun. 1949 - TLS Elaborate philosophical discussion, with three enclosures.
  - Mac Dowell, Mrs. Edward, 1935; 1937,; 1941; 3 Letters (Box 4)
    11 Apr. 1935 - ALS Mentions recommendation made by Hillyer and describes and discusses the character of the MacDowell colony.
    16 Jul. 1937 - ALS Discusses rejected applicants and invites Hillyer to the colony.
    2 Apr. 1941 - TLS
  - Machen, Arthur, 1922-1938; 99 Letters (Box 4)
    2 Nov. 1922 - Copy; Mentions Far Off Things and Things Near and Far.
    21 Nov. 1922 - Copy; States interest in New England and makes general comments.
    22 Mar. 1923 - Copy; Mentions The Process and discusses mystic experience.
    4 May 1923 - Copy; Praises both Hillyer's The Hills give Promise and review of Machen's book by Hillyer; mentions projected book.
    23 May 1923 - Copy; Mentions The Process and describes unfavorable review in The Boston Evening News.
    20 Sept. 1923 - Copy; Mentions Hillyer's review of Machen's work and his Essay on Epicurus and describes home county.
    24 Oct. 1923 - Copy; Discusses attitudes toward rationalism.
    25 Apr. 1924 - Copy; Comments on Emily Dickinson and book The Glorious Mystery; mentions Precious Balms.
    27 May 1924 - Copy; Mentions desire for a Harvard honorary degree and offers Hillyer aid in publishing poetry in England.
    9 Jul. 1924 - Copy; Agrees to write introduction for Hillyer's poems.
    4 Sept. 1924 - Copy; Comments on Precious Balms.
    15 Dec. 1924 - Copy; Mentions introduction for Hillyer's poems and forthcoming publication of book The Shining Pyramid.
    15 Jun. 1925 - Copy; Comments on American author, Miss Wilkins, and mentions book The Canning Wonder.
    23 Jul. 1925 - Copy; Comments on mysterious experience of Hillyer and inquires about Weathersfield, Connecticut.
    1 Aug. 1925 - Copy
    1 Sept. 1925 - Copy
    6 Nov. 1925 - Copy; Comments on changes in English life.
    25 Feb. 1926 - Copy
    29 Mar. 1926 - Copy
    4 May 1926 - Copy; Explains procedure by which foreigners can marry in England.
    20 May 1926 - Copy; Comments on Hillyer's decision to marry in America and on strike in England.
    17 Jun. 1926 - Copy; Comments on Hillyer's "Prothalamion."
    15 Jul. 1926 - Copy; Mentions Hillyer's plans to visit England.
    5 Aug. 1926 - Copy
    11 Aug. 1926 - Copy
    13 Aug. 1926 - Copy
    3 Sept. 1926 - Copy; Mentions success of unnamed Hillyer book.
    13 Oct. 1926 - Copy; Comments on changing meaning of words; encloses article.
    5 Nov. 1926 - Copy; Quotes original verse and compares Hillyer's life to his own.
    8 Dec. 1926 - Copy; Describes meeting of Washington Irving and Charles Dickens.
    1927 - Copy
    26 Feb. 1927 - Copy; Mentions article "Queer Things."
    7 Mar. 1927 - Copy; Comments on pleasure, reception of article "Queer Things," and tells Hillyer to send proofs of his book.
    30 Mar. 1927 - Copy; Mentions Hillyer's efforts to sell article "Queer Things."
    19 Apr. 1927 - Copy; Describes Bligh Bond.
    19 May 1927 - Copy
    4 Jun. 1927 - Copy; Congratulates Hillyer on birth of his son.
    8 Jun. 1927 - Copy
    30 Jun. 1927 - Copy
    7 Aug. 1927 - Copy
    13 Oct. 1927 - Copy; Describes author's fascination for country and difficulties in publication of "Fleet Street."
    22 Dec. 1927 - Copy; Comments on Hillyer's obtaining Harvard professorship.
    1 Feb. 1928 - Copy; Describes loss of former residence.
    9 Mar. 1928 - Copy; Thanks Hillyer for money donated by him.
    19 Mar. 1928 - Copy; Appreciation of Hillyer's The Seventh Hill.
    25 Apr. 1928 - Copy; Recounts trick played on an American correspondent and mentions Hillyer's "Manorbier."
    25 May 1928 - Copy
    11 Jul. 1928 - Copy
    18 Sept. 1928 - Copy; Describes holiday.
    1 Dec. 1928 - Copy; Discusses Hillyer's professorship and mentions "Fleet Street."
    8 Feb. 1929 - Copy; Mentions projected books by Cedric Smith and Odell Shepard.
    24 Apr. 1929 - Copy; Describes letter to A. E. Waite.
    16 Jun. 1929 - Copy; Describes new village to which Machen and family will move.
    16 Jul. 1929 - Copy; Comments on unidentified Phi Beta Kappa poem of Hillyer's and compares England and Connecticut; comments at length on being an expatriate.
    18 Sept. 1929 - Copy; Comments on architecture, describes attitude toward science and discusses education of son.
    13 Nov. 1929 - Copy; Grants Hillyer permission to select Machen item for publication and mentions work on revision of A. E. Waite's The Holy Kabbalah: A Study of the Secret Tradition in Israel.
    30 Dec. 1929 - Copy; Discusses Episcopal Church in England and America.
    20 Jan. 1930 - Copy; Encloses a copy of Country Life.
    29 Jan. 1930 - Copy; Thanks Hillyer for sending money and compares Hillyer's career to his own.
    4 Apr. 1930 - Copy; Describes the Lord of Broughton Castle.
    20 Jun. 1930 - Copy; Describes essay.
    21 Aug. 1930 - Copy; Comments on the state of western civilization.
    17 Nov. 1930 - Copy; Comments on Hillyer's The Gates of the Compass.
    29 Dec. 1930 - Copy; Comments on linguistic differentiations.
    27 Apr. 1931 - Copy
    12 Jun. 1931 - Copy
    21 Jul. 1931 - Copy; Comments on the League of Nations.
    21 Sept. 1931 - Copy; Discusses the possibility of revolution in America and England and comments on Russian developments.
    18 Jan. 1932 - Copy; Discusses Irish attempts to blot out English civilization in the Free State.
    2 Mar. 1932 - Copy
    28 Jun. 1932 - Copy; Comments at length on the Lindbergh kidnapping case.
    20 Oct. 1932 - Copy; Mentions Hillyer's novel Riverhead and comments on efforts to turn India into a democracy.
    17 Nov. 1932 - Copy; Mentions Galsworthy's reception of Nobel Prize.
    13 Jan. 1933 - Copy
    6 Jun. 1933 - Copy; Mentions lack of financial success of Hillyer's novel Riverhead, comments on his own financial state and deplores coming of self-government to India.
    23 Jul. 1933 - ALS
    18 Sept. 1933 - Copy
    8 Dec. 1933 - Copy; Comments on journalism and repeal of Prohibition.
    22 Jan. 1934 - Copy; Comments on modern age.
    31 Dec. 1934 - Copy
    22 Feb. 1935 - Copy; Describes lives of his two children, Hilary and Janet and mentions Odell Shepard.
    17 May 1935 - Copy; Discusses Anglicisms and Americanisms.
    1 Jun. 1936 - Copy; Mentions would-be biographers and makes further comments on India.
    28 Oct. 1936 - Copy; Comments on modern art and mentions T. S. Eliot.
    15 Dec. 1936 - Copy; Comments on certain literary figures and mentions Hitler.
    8 Dec. 1937 - Copy; Recounts events of last year in his own life.
    31 Jan. 1938 - Copy; Mentions Hillyer's obtaining Boylston Chair and describes large numbers of Americans flowing into London.
    10 Mar. 1938 - Copy; Mentions Pascal, Plato, Hamlet, and describes Mrs. Norah Hoults' work.
    12 Mar. 1938 - ALS Encloses book in which is contained author's The Green Round.
    24 May 1938 - Copy
    14 Jun. 1938 - Copy; Speaks of Holy Grail legend.
    6 Sept. 1938 - Copy; Mentions Hillyer's health, translation project; comments on Progress and Catastrophe by Stanley Casson.
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1935; 1938,; undated; 7 Letters (Box 4)
    17 Jan. - TLS Discusses injustice.
    15 Jan. 1935 - TLS
    7 Oct. 1938 - TLS
    10 Nov. 1938 - TLS
    22 Nov. 1938 - TLS
    7 Dec. 1938 - TLS Discusses Frost proposal.
    20 Dec. 1938 - TLS
  - Marcum, Howard, 1962; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    5 Mar. 1962 - ALS Mentions research paper on Hillyer's First Principles of Verse and requests critical comment on poetry of unidentified person for inclusion therein.
  - Marcus, J. Anthony, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    4 Jul. 1949 - TLS Praises Hillyer's stand on Bollingen Award and offers help in pursuing the matter further.
  - Mason, Daniel G., 1947-1951; 18 Letters (Box 4)
    12 Aug. 1947 - TLS Lengthy appreciation of Hillyer's poems in The Lyric's summer issue.
    22 Aug. 1947 - TLS
    8 Nov. 1947 - TLS
    12 Jan. 1948 - TLS Mentions publication of article "Music for Sharing."
    23 Jun. 1948 - TLS Discusses work of poet Riggs.
    12 Jul. 1948 - TLS
    18 Aug. 1948 - TLS
    29 Aug. 1948 - TLS
    30 Aug. 1948 - ALS Sends copies of praise for Mason's Symphony No. 1 and comments on Hillyer's opinion of poet Riggs.
    16 Nov. 1948 - TLS Encloses copy of Ridgeley Torrence's parody of E. A. Robinson.
    17 Nov. 1948 - TLS Describes National Institute of Arts and Letters opening dinner of the season and compares thought of Joseph Wood Krutch and Hillyer on Thoreau.
    30 Dec. 1948 - TLS Discusses Stravinsky's admission to National Institute of Arts and Letters, discusses current musical activity of author, and encloses copies of E. B. White poem and fan letter.
    16 Oct. 1949 - TLS Discusses forthcoming performances of Mason's Symphony No. 1.
    24 Oct. 1949 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's reaction to earlier attack on Bollingen Award and describes performance of Symphony No. 1 at Eastman School of Music.
    16 Jan. 1950 - TLS Comments on members of the National Institute of Arts and Letters and on current literary activity.
    6 May 1950 - TLS Comments on resurgence of music.
    22 Nov. 1950 - TLS Describes current musical activity and Ridgeley Torrence's health.
    24 Jan. 1951 - TLS Appreciation of Hillyer's A Letter to Robert Frost and Others and a description of the last days of Ridgeley Torrence.
  - Maxwell, William, 1932; 1938,; 1949,; undated; 11 Letters, 2 Cards (Box 4)
    Undated - ALS Comments on Hillyer's A Letter to Robert Frost and Others.